Guide to the University Career Services, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
University Career Services, Yale University, records
1950-1990
RU 717
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
161.75
The records consist of materials concerning the Master of Arts in Teaching (M.A.T.) degree, teacher placement, pre-medical students, fellowship applications, scholarships, reports on Yale Conferences on the Teaching of Social Studies and English, and the National Science Foundation Summer Institute. Also included are registration cards, minutes, correspondence, memoranda, reports, budgets, and administrative files of Undergraduate Career Services (formerly) Yale University Career Services.
Yale University. University Career Services
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-E (YRG 9-E), Records documenting Yale College offices, programs, and projects.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of materials concerning the Master of Arts in Teaching (M.A.T.) degree, teacher placement, pre-medical students, fellowship applications, scholarships, reports on Yale Conferences on the Teaching of Social Studies and English, and the National Science Foundation Summer Institute. Also included are registration cards, minutes, correspondence, memoranda, reports, budgets, and administrative files of Undergraduate Career Services (formerly) Yale University Career Services.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
College placement services; Teachers -- Selection and appointment; Teachers -- Training of; Teaching; National Science Foundation (U.S.). Summer Institute; Yale College (1887- ). Dean's Office; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. University Career Services
- Pre-medical and special category student records, 1950-1977; Accession 1977-A-009
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2052
  - CAREER ADVISORY AND PLACEMENT SERVICE (CAPS) PRE-MED FILES
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1–4)
  - 1950 and before (Box 5)
  - 1951-1954 (Box 5)
  - A-L, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Special students, 1955-1959 (Box 6)
  - R-Z, 1955 (Box 6)
  - A-Z, 1956 (Box 6)
  - A-K, 1957 (Box 6)
  - L -W, 1957 (Box 7)
  - A-F, 1958 (Box 7)
  - G-Y, 1958 (Box 8)
  - B -M, 1959 (Box 9)
  - N-Z, 1959 (Box 10)
  - Chemistry and physics, 1959 (Box 10)
  - A -F, 1960 (Box 10)
  - G-Z, 1960 (Box 11)
  - A-P, 1961 (Box 12)
  - R-W, 1961 (Box 13)
  - A-Gi, 1962 (Box 13)
  - Gl-Z, 1962 (Box 14)
  - A-M, 1963 (Box 15)
  - N-Z, 1963 (Box 16)
  - A-Co, 1964 (Box 16)
  - Po-Z, 1964 (Box 18)
  - A-Ch, 1965 (Box 18)
  - Co-P, 1965 (Box 19)
  - O-Z, 1965 (Box 20)
  - Special, 1965 (Box 20)
  - A-Ch, 1966 (Box 20)
  - Co-M, 1966 (Box 21)
  - N-Z, 1966 (Box 22)
  - Special, 1966 (Box 22)
  - A-Ma, 1967 (Box 23)
  - Me-Z, 1967 (Box 24)
  - A-Le, 1968 (Box 25)
  - Li-Z, 1968 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1968 (Box 27)
  - A-L, 1969 (Box 28)
  - M-Z, 1969 (Box 29)
  - A-Ha, 1970 (Box 30)
  - He-Ri, 1970 (Box 31)
  - Ro-S, 1970 (Box 32)
  - A-Ga, 1971 (Box 32)
  - Ge -Pek, 1971 (Box 33)
  - Per-Z, 1971 (Box 34)
  - A-H, 1972 (Box 35)
  - I-Si, 1972 (Box 36)
  - Sl-Z, 1972 (Box 37)
  - Special, 1972 (Box 37)
  - A-C, 1973 (Box 37)
  - D-K, 1973 (Box 38)
  - L-Sc, 1973 (Box 39)
  - Si-Z, 1973 (Box 40)
  - Special, 1972-1973 (Box 40)
  - A-Go, 1974 (Box 41)
  - Gr -N, 1974 (Box 42)
  - O-W, Evaluations, 1974 (Box 43)
  - Inactive: A-S, P-W, 1974 (Box 44)
  - Special: A-Pa, 1974 (Box 45)
  - Special: Pe-Z, 1974 (Box 46)
  - A-Goo, 1975 (Box 47)
  - Got-Pl, 1975 (Box 48)
  - Po-Z, 1975 (Box 49)
  - Special: A-S, 1975 (Box 50)
  - Special: T-Z, 1975 (Box 51)
  - A-E, 1976 (Box 51)
  - F-O, 1976 (Box 52)
  - P-Z, 1976 (Box 53)
  - Special: A-R, 1976 (Box 54)
  - Special: S-Z, 1976 (Box 55)
  - A-F, 1977 (Box 55)
  - G-N, 1977 (Box 56)
  - O-W, 1977 (Box 57)
  - Y-Z, 1977 (Box 58)
  - Special: A-P, 1977 (Box 58)
  - Special: R-Z, 1977 (Box 59)
  - Inactive: A-Z, 1977 (Box 59)
- Pre-medical and fellowship program student records, 1970-1979; Accession 1982-A-029
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2054
  - Medical School Applicants
    - Class of 1978, A-K (Box 1)
    - Class of 1978, L-Z (Box 2)
    - Special Category, 1978, A-S (Box 3)
    - Special Category, 1978, T-Z (Box 4)
    - Class of 1979, A-J (Box 5)
    - Class of 1979, K-Z (Box 6)
    - Special Category, 1979, A-L (Box 7)
    - Special Category, 1979, M-Z (Box 8)
  - Junior Year Abroad, Classes of 1976, 1977, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Murray Fellowship Applicants, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Churchill Applicants, 1976-1978 (Box 10)
  - Murray Fellowship Applicants, 1973-1979 (Box 11)
  - Beinecke Applicants, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
  - Danforth Applicants, 1973-1977 (Box 12)
  - Fulbright Applicants, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
  - Griswold Applicants, 1974-1978 (Box 12)
  - Howland Applicants, 1967- 1968 (Box 12)
  - Luce Applicants, 1975-1978 (Box 12)
  - Mellon Applicants, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Rhodes Applicants, 1968-1977 (Box 12)
  - Truman Applicants, 1976-1978 (Box 12)
  - Management Trainee project applicants, Spring 1977 (Box 12)
- Fellowship program student records, 1968-1980; Accession 1983-A-055
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2055
  - Fellowship program
    - Committee (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Papers (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beinecke Memorial Scholarship
    - Applicants:
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Papers (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Churchill Foundation Scholarship
    - Applicants:
    - Committee (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Nominees (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Papers (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Corning Traveling Fellowship
    - Applicants:
    - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Papers (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - DAAD (Deutscher Akademigcher austaushdienst)
    - Applicants:
    - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Nominees (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Papers (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Danforth-Graduate Fellowship Program
    - Applicants:
    - Committee (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Nominees (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Papers (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Fulbright Fellowship
    - Applicants A-Z (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Newsletters (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Papers (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Recipients (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Rejections (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Luce Fellowship
    - Applicants:
    - Committee (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Nominees (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Papers (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Marshall Scholarships
    - Applicants (see Rhodes Scholarship, Applicants) (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Papers (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Murray Fellowship
    - Applicants
    - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - Nominees (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - Papers (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Proposal (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - Supporting material (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - National Science Foundation
    - Correspondence/papers (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - Rhodes Scholarships
    - Applicants (lists) (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Applicants" essays (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - Papers (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - Truman, Harry S., Scholarship
    - Applicants
    - Committee (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - Nominees (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - Papers (Box 7, Folder 163)
- Pre-medical student records, 1980-1981; Accession 1984-A-034
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2056
  - A-K, 1980 (Box 1)
  - L-Z, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Special Category A-P, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Special Category R-Z, 1980 (Box 4)
  - A-F, 1981 (Box 4)
  - G-Sh, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Sk-Z, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Special Category A-H, 1981 (Box 6)
- Pre-medical, fellowship program, and Junior Year Abroad student records, 1954-1985; Accession 1985-A-016
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2060
  - Fellowships and Scholarships
    - Fellowships - General
      - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Program Papers, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Griswold Scholarship Papers, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Henry Fellowships, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Luce Fellowship
      - General (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Management Trainee Project (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Marshall, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Mellon Fellowship Discretionary Account 6 6317 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - National Science Foundation
      - General (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Rhodes Scholarships
      - General (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - through 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Fellowship Procedures, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Harry S. Truman Scholarship, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Fellowship Winners, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Past Fellowship Committees (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Bates Fellowship, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Beinecke Memorial Scholarship, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Carnegie
      - Endowment for International Peace (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Churchill Fellowship
      - 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - Material, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Coro Foundation, 1967-1975 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Danforth Fellowship
      - 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - 1974-1975 (Applicants) (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 59)
      - Papers (Box 1, Folder 60)
      - 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Corning-Howtand Traveling Fellowship
      - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Deutscher Akademischer Austauschdienst (DAAD)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 86)
      - Nominees, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Danforth Fellowships
      - Papers, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 91)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 92)
      - Extra Letters not to be used (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Fullbright Fellowships
      - General (Box 2, Folder 111)
      - Special Award Program to Syria (Box 2, Folder 112)
      - Extra Letters not to be used (Box 2, Folder 116)
      - Applications given out, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 117)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 118)
      - Papers, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Marshall Scholarship
      - Applicants (Box 2, Folder 137)
      - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 138)
      - Papers (Box 2, Folder 139)
    - Rhodes Scholarship
      - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 140)
      - Applicants (Box 2, Folder 141)
      - Papers (Box 2, Folder 142)
      - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 142b)
      - Papers, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 142c)
      - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 142d)
      - Papers, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 142e)
    - Luce Scholarship
      - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 143)
      - Nominees (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Truman Scholarship
      - Papers (Box 3, Folder 156)
      - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 157 - 158)
    - Carey Scholarships
      - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 177)
      - Papers (Box 3, Folder 178)
      - Nominees (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - Churchill Scholarships
      - Material (Box 3, Folder 183)
      - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 184)
      - Nominees (empty) (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - National Science Foundation
      - Papers (Box 3, Folder 192)
      - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 193)
      - Fellowship Committees (Box 3, Folder 194)
      - Fellowship Statistics (Box 3, Folder 195)
      - Fellowship Mailing List (Box 3, Folder 196)
      - Committee Letters (Box 3, Folder 197)
      - Papers (Box 3, Folder 198)
      - Bouquets (Box 3, Folder 199)
  - Pre-Medical Studies
    - General, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - Correspondence with Medical Schools (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Old Pre-Med Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - Correspondence
      - 1978 Jul-Sep (Box 4, Folder 203)
      - 1978 Oct-Dec (Box 4, Folder 204)
      - 1979 Jan-Mar (Box 4, Folder 205)
      - 1979 Apr-Jun (Box 4, Folder 206)
      - 1979 Jul-Sep (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - 1975
      - Apr (Box 4, Folder 208)
      - May (Box 4, Folder 209)
      - Jun (Box 4, Folder 210)
      - Jul (Box 4, Folder 211)
      - Aug (Box 4, Folder 212)
      - Sep (Box 4, Folder 213)
      - Oct (Box 4, Folder 214)
      - Nov (Box 4, Folder 215)
      - Dec (Box 4, Folder 216)
    - 1976
      - Jan (Box 4, Folder 217)
      - Feb (Box 4, Folder 218)
      - Mar (Box 4, Folder 219)
      - Apr (Box 4, Folder 220)
      - May (Box 4, Folder 221)
      - Jun (Box 4, Folder 222)
      - Jul (Box 4, Folder 223)
      - Aug (Box 4, Folder 224)
      - Sep (Box 4, Folder 225)
      - Oct (Box 4, Folder 226)
      - Nov (Box 4, Folder 227)
      - Dec (Box 4, Folder 228)
    - 1977
      - Jan (Box 4, Folder 229)
      - Feb (Box 4, Folder 230)
      - Mar (Box 4, Folder 231)
      - Apr (Box 4, Folder 232)
      - May (Box 4, Folder 233)
      - Jun (Box 4, Folder 234)
      - Jul (Box 4, Folder 235)
      - Aug (Box 4, Folder 236)
      - Sep (Box 4, Folder 237)
      - Oct-Nov (Box 4, Folder 238)
  - Junior Year Abroad
    - Class of 1979
      - General (Box 5, Folder 239)
    - Class of 1980 (Box 5)
    - Class of 1981
      - Check Lists for Class of 1981 (Box 5, Folder 326)
    - Class of 1975
    - Class of 1982
      - Check Lists (Box 6, Folder 365)
- Pre-medical student records, 1982; Accession 1986-A-083
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2057
  - Inactive-Class of 1982
  - Premed Students-Special Category
  - Inactive-1982
  - Incompletes-1982
- Records relating to the Fulbright Scholarship Committee, 1967-1976; Accession 1987-A-088
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2051
  - Institute of Internal Education Publications, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Candidates for Study in Australia/New Zealand, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Undated Materials (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Pre-medical, fellowship program, and Junior Year Abroad records, 1980-1986; Accession 1987-A-110
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2061
  - Junior Year Abroad-Class of 1986-Applicants
  - Fellowship Files
    - 1980-1981
      - Publicity for Fellowships (Box 2, Folder 118)
      - Fellowship Committees (Box 2, Folder 119)
      - Committee Fellowship Letters (Box 2, Folder 120)
      - Fellowship Revisions (Box 2, Folder 121)
      - College Level Examination Program (C. L. E. P.) Information (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Office of Foreign Students: Scholars Information (Box 2, Folder 123)
      - Fellowship Program Papers (Box 2, Folder 124)
      - Bouquets (Box 2, Folder 125)
      - Carey Scholarship (Box 2, Folder 126)
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 2, Folder 127 - 128)
        - Applicants
      - Churchill Scholarship
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 2, Folder 132 - 133)
        - Applicants
      - Daad Scholarship
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 2, Folder 139 - 140)
        - Applicants
      - Danforth Fellowship
        - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 145)
      - Murray Fellowship
        - Applicants
      - Files and Information
        - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 192)
        - Papers (Box 2, Folder 193)
        - Report (Box 2, Folder 194)
      - Fulbright Fellowship papers (Box 3, Folder 195)
      - Luce Scholarship
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 3, Folder 196)
        - Applicants
      - Marshall Scholarship Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 216)
      - Corning-Howland Correspondence and Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 217 - 218)
      - National Science Foundation: Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 219)
      - Rhodes Scholarship: Correspondence and Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 220 - 221)
      - Truman Scholarship
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 3, Folder 222 - 223)
        - Applicants
    - 1981-1982
      - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 240)
      - Committees (Box 3, Folder 241)
      - Guide
        - Book (Box 3, Folder 242)
        - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 243)
        - Corrections/Additions (Box 3, Folder 244)
        - Revisions (Box 3, Folder 245)
    - 1981-1983
      - Programs (Box 3, Folder 246)
      - Programs/Bouquets (Box 3, Folder 247)
      - Publicity (Box 3, Folder 248)
      - Reception: Spring Invitation List (Box 3, Folder 249)
      - Alice Freeman Palmer Fellowship: Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 250)
      - Lewis Curtis Fellowship for Travel (Box 3, Folder 252)
      - Robert Stewart Kilborne Fellowship (Box 3, Folder 254)
      - Alice Freeman Palmer Fellowship
        - Tic Sheet (Box 3, Folder 255)
        - Applicants
      - Beinecke Scholarship, 1981-1982
        - Correspondence and papers (Box 3, Folder 258 - 259)
        - Applicants
      - Churchill Scholarship, 1981-1982
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 3, Folder 270 - 271)
        - Applicants
      - Carey Scholarship, 1981-1982
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 3, Folder 278 - 279)
        - Applicants
      - Daad Fellowship, 1981-1982
        - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 283)
        - Applicants
      - Fulbright-Hays Scholarship, 1981-1982
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 4, Folder 294)
        - Additional Materials (Box 4, Folder 295)
        - Responses to Applicants (Box 4, Folder 296)
      - Howland Fellowship, 1981-1982
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 4, Folder 297 - 298)
        - Applicants
      - Marshall Scholarship, 1981-1982
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 4, Folder 313 - 314)
      - Luce Scholars Program, 1981-1982
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 4, Folder 315 - 316)
        - Applicants
      - NSF Fellowships (National Science Foundation), 1981-1982
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 4, Folder 333 - 334)
      - St. Andrew"s Society Scholarship, 1981-1982
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 4, Folder 335 - 336)
        - Applicants
      - Truman Scholarship
        - Correspondence and Papers (Box 4, Folder 342)
        - Applicants
      - Inquiry Card File (Box 4, Folder 363)
      - Rhodes and Marshall Scholarship (blank applications), 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 364)
    - Cambridge and Oxford Programs, 1981-1982
      - Junior Year Abroad (Box 4, Folder 365)
      - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 366)
    - Fellowship Applicant Folders (list) (Box 4, Folder 367)
    - Murray Fellowship
      - Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 368)
      - Applicants
      - Fellowship Office Information, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 398)
        - Committees (Box 5, Folder 399)
        - Weekly Bulletin, calendar and information sheets (Box 5, Folder 400 - 402)
        - Index Corrections (Box 5, Folder 403)
        - Programs-Bouquests (Box 5, Folder 404)
        - Posters (Box 5, Folder 405 - 407)
        - Masters: Information sheets, applications (Box 5, Folder 408)
        - Guide: additions and corrections (Box 5, Folder 409)
        - Sign-In Log (Box 5, Folder 410)
        - Correspondence and papers (Box 5, Folder 411 - 412)
        - Algorithms (Box 5, Folder 413)
    - Beinecke Scholarship, 1982-1983
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 5, Folder 414 - 415)
      - Applications
    - Blanning Summer Memorial Fellowship, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 427 - 428)
    - Carey Scholarship, 1982-1983
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 5, Folder 429 - 430)
      - Applicants
    - Carnegie Endowment, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 432 - 433)
    - Churchill Scholarship, 1982-1983
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 5, Folder 434 - 435)
      - Applicants
    - Connecticut Bankers Scholarship: Correspondence and Papers, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 437 - 438)
    - DAAD Scholarship, 1982-1983
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 5, Folder 439 - 440)
      - Applicants
    - Fulbright Fellowship, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 447)
      - Applicants
        - New Fulbrights (Box 5, Folder 448)
        - Tic Sheets (Box 5, Folder 451)
        - Responses to Applicants (Box 5, Folder 454)
    - Howland Fellowship, 1982-1983
      - Tic Sheets (Box 5, Folder 455)
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 5, Folder 456 - 457)
      - Applicants
    - ASME (American Society of Magazine Editors), 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 472 - 473)
    - Cambridge Prospectus, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 474)
    - International Computer Programs: Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 475)
    - Keasbey Fellowship, 1982-1983
      - Papers (Box 6, Folder 476)
      - Applicants
    - Luce Scholars Program, 1982-1983
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 6, Folder 522 - 523)
      - Applicants
    - Marshall Scholarship: Correspondence and Papers, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 539 - 540)
    - Mellon Fellowship: Correspondence and Papers, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 541 - 542)
    - Murray Fellowship, 1982-1983
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 6, Folder 543 - 544)
      - Applicants
    - NSF (National Science Foundation): Correspondence and Papers, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 574 - 575)
    - Time: Internship and Magazine, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 576 - 577)
    - St. Andrew's Society, 1982-1983
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 6, Folder 578 - 579)
      - Applicants
    - Truman Scholarship, 1982-1983
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 7, Folder 587 - 588)
      - Applicants
  - Fellowship Programs, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 612)
    - Bouquets (Box 7, Folder 613)
    - Calendar (Box 7, Folder 614)
    - Committees (Box 7, Folder 615)
    - Chronological File (Box 7, Folder 616)
    - Guide: additions and corrections (Box 7, Folder 617)
    - Labels: mailing (Box 7, Folder 618)
    - Office sign-in sheet (Box 7, Folder 619)
    - Posters (Box 7, Folder 620 - 621)
    - Statistics (Box 7, Folder 622)
    - Suggestions (Box 7, Folder 623)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 624)
    - Beinecke Scholarship, 1983-1984
      - Basic information (Box 7, Folder 625)
        - Correspondence and papers (Box 7, Folder 626 - 627)
        - Memoranda (Box 7, Folder 628)
        - Applicants
    - Blanning Fellowship, 1983-1984
      - Basic information (Box 7, Folder 639)
      - Correspondence and papers (Box 7, Folder 640 - 641)
      - Applicants
    - Carey Scholarship, 1983-1984
      - Basic information (Box 7, Folder 653)
      - Forms (Box 7, Folder 654)
      - Correspondence and papers (Box 7, Folder 655 - 656)
      - Memoranda (Box 7, Folder 657)
      - Members (Box 7, Folder 658)
      - Applicant
    - Carnegie Endowment, 1983-1984
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 7, Folder 660 - 661)
      - Forms (Box 7, Folder 662)
      - Applicants, 1983-1984
    - Churchill Scholarship, 1983-1984
      - Basic information (Box 7, Folder 672)
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 7, Folder 673 - 674)
      - Memoranda (Box 7, Folder 675)
      - Committee members (Box 7, Folder 676)
      - Forms (Box 7, Folder 677)
      - Applicants
    - DAAD Scholarship, 1983-1984
      - Basic information (Box 7, Folder 683)
      - Forms (Box 7, Folder 684)
      - Correspondence and Papers (Box 7, Folder 685 - 686)
      - Memoranda (Box 7, Folder 687)
      - Committee members (Box 7, Folder 688)
      - Applicants
    - Dorot Fellowship, 1983-1984
      - Basic information (Box 8, Folder 695)
      - Finances (Box 8, Folder 696)
      - Committee members (lacking) (Box 8, Folder 697)
      - Correspondence and papers (Box 8, Folder 698 - 699)
      - Forms (Box 8, Folder 700)
      - Memoranda (Box 8, Folder 701)
      - Applicants
      - Tic Sheets (Box 8, Folder 718)